A Guide to the Broad Street Improvements-Papers of Sue Bachtel, 1963-1991
Mary Riley Styles Public Library
- Broad St. Improvements – 1988 (Box-folder 2-15)
  - VDOT public hearing March 17
  - Olom letter to VDH&T, March 27
  - Mayor statement to VDOT April 22
  - Bachtel statement to mayor and council, April 25
  - WP clipping, June 2
  - Ballot question: Just say no
  - Bachtel letter to commission, June 16
  - Statement by mayor, June 16
  - Beasley letter, June 17
  - Letter from governor to mayor, July 7
  - Various correspondence, July-September
- Broad St. Improvements – 1989 (Box-folder 2-16)
  - Memorandum from city attorney to mayor, January 27
  - Letter to counsel from city attorney, February 9
  - Status memorandum, February 27
  - WP clipping, March 9, 1989
  - Memorandum from city attorney to mayor, March 21
  - Memorandum from director of pw o city manager, April 13
  - Letter from VDOT, April
  - Memorandums from city manager to mayor, April 19, 21, May 3
  - Resolution to VDOT, May 8
  - Memorandum from city manager to mayor, June 9
  - Village Way, June 1989
  - Ordinance, June
  - Edits to ordinance, June 12
  - Memorandum and background paper from FCCO to FCCO board, June 15
  - Citizen letter, June 19
  - N.Va Sun clipping, July 19
  - Memorandum from city attorney to mayor, June 19, 21
  - Ordinance, June 26
  - Resolution, June 26
  - Citizen letters to city clerk, July 1, 6
  - Memorandum from city manager to mayor, July 6
  - Memorandum to city manager, July 7
  - WP clipping, July 8
  - Citizen letters to mayor, July 10
  - Memorandum from city manager, July 10
  - Citizen letters (7) to mayor and council, July 17
  - Falls Church Citizens’ Organization letter to mayor and council, July 17, 2 copies
  - Bachtel faxes to WP, N.Va. Sun, and FC Gazette reporters, July 18
  - Citizen letter to mayor and council, July 18
  - Police Department memorandum regarding accidents on Broad St.
  - Agenda for July 18 recessed city council meeting
  - Resolution 89-23
  - Letter to Arlington Co. chief judge from city attorney, July20
  - Memorandum regarding width of Duke of Gloucester St., July21
  - WP clipping, July 27
  - Press release, July 28
  - Letter from Bachtel and Olom to Virginia Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety, July 31
  - Letter from City Attorney to mayor and council, August 11
  - Draft of Focus article on referendum, August 11
  - Memorandum from city attorney to mayor and council, August 17
  - Business spotlight article, August
  - Notes on Broad St. coalition meeting, August 29
  - Agenda of coalition for broad street bonds meeting, August 30
  - Memorandum from FCCO to council, August 30
  - Letter to citizen from director of planning, August 31
  - Referendum, September 6
  - Letter from former VPIS presidents to current president, September 12
  - FCCO News, September
  - Referendum West Broad Street Improvements, September
  - FCCO News, vol 2, no 3, September
  - FCCO letter to citizens, September 13
  - Groups against the referendum, September
  - Letter from former VPIS presidents to current president, September 14
  - Bachtel notes October
  - Letter to PTA from committee to vote no…, October 11
  - Letter from Giant Food, vice president of public affairs, November 2
  - Fairfax Journal clipping, November 3
  - Bachtel notes
  - WP editorial, November 4
  - Citizen letter, November 4
  - Flyers of Just vote no committee
  - Election results, November 8
  - WP clipping, November 8
- Broad St. Improvements – 1990, 1991 (Box-folder 2-17)
  - Memorandum from director of public works to city manager, September 10, 1990
  - Memorandum to city council from city manager, December 14, 1990
  - Citizen memo to Virginia state delegates and senators, January 11, 1991
  - Broad Street Construction Update newsletter, January 20
  - Memorandum from city manager to city council, February 25
  - Letter to mayor from Broad St Civic Association, March 25
  - Letter from vice mayor to district administration VDOT, April 5
  - Fax from Gary Fuller to Bachtel, April 24
  - Memorandum from city manager to mayor and council, April 26
  - Letter from Lawrence Pence to Commonwealth Transportation Board, May 8
  - Memorandum from city manager to council, June 4
  - Traffic counts, June 24
  - Memorandum from director of public works to city manager, July 24
  - Invitation to ground breaking ceremony, July 12
  - Fax from VDOT to Bachtel, July 30
  - FCCO letter to citizens, September
  - Memorandum from economic development coordinator to director of planning, November 15
  - Notes to council from city manager, November 15
  - Letter to West Broad St. businesses from Bachtel, November 17
  - Flyer from Greater Falls Church Chamber of Commerce, November 18
  - Letter to city manager from business owner, November 19
  - Letter from Lawrence Pence to Virginia delegates and senators, December 10